<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>My edict royal</title>
            <author>Tany, Thomas, fl. 1649-1655.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1655</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 46 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A94532</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T152C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R232368</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99897965</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99897965</idno>
            <idno type="VID">133404</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A94532)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 133404)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2557:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>My edict royal</title>
                  <author>Tany, Thomas, fl. 1649-1655.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>30 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1655?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: ThauRam Tanjah Rex Israel &amp; Anglise, i.e. Thomas Tany.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Henry E. Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ranters --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>God --  Wrath --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-12</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-12</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="tract">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:133404:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>My EDICT Royal.</head>
            <div type="part">
               <p>HEar O <hi>England,</hi> God will ſunder thee into ſmall peices, as the Finer doth fill his melting pot; for Jehovah his fierce wrath is kindled for to pluck up root and branch, for the ſoul of the Land crieth un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Lord, for the fierce vengance to be poured upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> oppreſſors, for God will thunder from Heaven upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>e habitation of wickedneſs, for the whole Land is run <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>o perjury againſt the Holy One of <hi>Iſrael;</hi> for thus ſaith God, Your Faith, your Oaths, your Proteſtation, your Covenants, your Faſts, your Vows, in all theſe your Souls ſtand bound; which Covenants and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracts God doth call to ſeal with your blood thereby, for to free your Souls from the death of Hell, in whichye ſhall be bound till every Covenant be fully ſatisfi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, every mans Spirit both dead and alive have ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction.</p>
               <p>Therefore houl, houl, houl, houl houl, houl, that is, your ſix dayes work, the creation ſimptome, 6000 yeers before the expiation of your ſufferings.</p>
               <p>Thus ſaith Jehovah the great King, The whole Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment of this Nation is accurſed before me; di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ge your conſciences, your hearts, and your bloody hands, and then ſeek me empty, naked, clean, without your own wiſdom, and then I will inſpire life, righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ousneſs, that thereby your ſouls may feed on me; but <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> are Traytors againſt my righteous Son Jeſus, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> pure Law which ye ſo often name, and alwayes
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:133404:2"/>tranſgreſs, making it your image of ſtealth, that by its pretence ye have cloaked your villany, and robbed the Nations liberty. Thus ſaith God, Am I a theif? am I a Covenant-breaker? am I a murderer? am I a falſe witneſs bearer? am I a circumventor? am I an idola<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor? am I a lyer? am I an oppreſſor? or am I unjuſt? or am I a perjured one? No; I am holy, and ye wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed hell-hounds are all that is there declared.</p>
               <p>Thus ſaith Jehovah, An Offering I require from the whole ſeſſion conveened, that is one peice of ſilver that is not thus polluted, either by couſning, cheating, op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion, murder, deceit, fellon, profane blaſphemy. Covenant-breaking, ſacriledge, robbery, free from the blood of the Widdow, and fatherleſs, innocent and ſimple; but ye are a conſpiracy of <hi>Cain,</hi> that wicked one that ſlew the innocent, and ye are wicked rebels, Traytors againſt the Lord, this Nation, and the peace of your own Souls; and ye are that bloſomed whore, that daring the Sun, Men and Angels, preſcribe me my way to be ſerved in their form.</p>
               <p>This is Gods Word in the Mount of <hi>Iſrael</hi>'s King, unto the Covenant-breakers: God will cut you off every one man, woman, and childe in his fierce wrath, and he will give you your portion with the damned Spirits in Hell fire, to be tormented day and night for ever, THAU.</p>
               <p>Thus ſaith Jehovah, I ſent my Meſſenger to ſhew the fierce wrath that is kindled in me againſt ye Rebels, that tranſgreſs your Covenant for a frown of a mortal man, whoſe breath is vain, his ſtrength corruption.</p>
               <p>Thus ſaith Jehovah that made man and all things Do you reverence and fear duſt, nay, the worſt of men, and dare you tranſgreſs the Commands of God, he
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:133404:2"/> is the life of the Creation.</p>
               <p>Thus ſaith God, Becauſe ye fear man more then me, into the hands of men have I given your lives, your wives and children that know not me, and they ſhall deal with you, as they that know not God, do unto Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels and Traytors againſt Gods Covenant, the Peoples Cauſe, the Nations Liberty, by you from the juſt own<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers detained.</p>
               <p>And hear now ye Traytors and Rebels againſt Jeho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vah, he will be avenged on you all, and for this cauſe, firſt you judged every one in the notion of publique Faith. Faith is Gods holdment of the Soul unto him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf by pure obedience in man. Faith is the glorious demonſtrator of God in man unto men his fellow crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, as men and women in Nations and Countries.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>Thus ſaith God, Becauſe you have made my Name to be by you blaſphemed in all Countryes adjacent, ſo will I make the ſound of your puniſhment, ſound as loud and large an eccho: firſt, you falſified your truſt to you committed, and let my honour and glory fall to be nothing worth, thereby to make your ſelves great by robing all that ever engaged with an honeſt heart in my Name. So were they cozened by your pretended Faith, my Covenant; and by this, cheat the Souldiers, wages that the Nations Faith was ingaged for to pay: it fell from 20 <hi>s.</hi> unto 2.6. and 169 <hi>s.</hi> Remember <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Norwoods</hi> Sail, and then the publick Faith at 1 <hi>s.</hi> a pound, and 1 s. and 4 <hi>d.</hi> are there not brave rates, yea, Traytors for Gods holy Covenant to be bought and ſold by perjured perſons: the poor lands muſt truſt, and cheat.</p>
               <p>Thus when it was let fall thus long, your Emmiſſio
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:133404:3"/>did purchaſe it, and the ſummes are gathered into one great ſum. Then you ſtate your land where you pleaſe, and cauſe a falſe value to be ſet on it; that for one pound, that coſt you one ſhilling four pence, the value of four pound, nay ſome 4 <hi>l.</hi> this is villany, and out of villany you muſt erect us a form of God-ſerving: No, you ſhall not lay your wicked yoke upon our neck, God will deliver us from ye accurſed men.</p>
               <p>Thus God hath delivered you into the hands of them that ſeek your lives, the Lands Liberty. Take notice people I ſee the cauſe ſtated upon which the effect doth proceed, which is this judgement. The chief Actors in this conſpiracy againſt the Lord God Almighty ſhall be taken, and their gold and ſilver put in pots, and they ſtaked in the middle of their ſtuff, and ſo be burnt to aſhes, their wives and children ſlain with the ſword, and if with childe, the childe the ſpaun of their luſt, broyled on the coals, their kindred ſlain aſcending and deſcending, their Lands return unto the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth to pay the Souldier and the publick Faith, that they have ſo traiterouſly betrayed. This is the Word from Jehovah upon the Rebels.</p>
               <p>And further, their whole Lands in this cauſe to be accounted felons goods, and to return by the Statute of Trover and Converſion.</p>
               <p>And thus ſaith God, All Lands and Conveyances, that have been paſſed by theſe men, ſhall return to be diſpoſed by the Commonwealth, as it is true Lord o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver all that it did imploy, out of which the poor ſhall have a ſufficiency, that they may praiſe Jehovah for his mercy; but for my part not one penny, for I go for <hi>FRANCE,</hi> and to <hi>ROME,</hi> and ſo to <hi>JERUS ALEM;</hi> onely my Title, the whole Forreſt-Lands named <hi>Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bion,</hi>
                  <pb n="5" facs="tcp:133404:3"/>now named <hi>England,</hi> as Heir apparent unto King <hi>Stephen;</hi> and in my Title was <hi>Richard</hi> the ſecond, and in my holdment from <hi>BARRON TONI</hi> the ancient Forreſter of <hi>England,</hi> and likewiſe our Title of <hi>ABBAR GAUVENI,</hi> in which Title lies my LORD PRO<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>TECTOR's holdment unto his true Line; but the LORD hath cut him off and his iſſue, onely in <hi>Clapool</hi> is ſomething found. As I am a man, my ſoul mourns; but GOD's Word muſt be wrote THAU, for he is my younger Brother's Son.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>Thus ſaith JEHOVAH, I have ſent unto him by breathings, and he will contemne me even before Men and Angels.</p>
               <p>Therefore ſaith the LORD, Write this man, and his whole iſſue to deſtruction every one, onely in <hi>Clapool</hi> is ſomewhat found.</p>
               <p>This is wrote the 12 day of the firſt Month, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded by JEHOVAH, AB, ſignifying the deliverance of my people the Jews.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>Now I ſhall declare unto the whole earth the cauſe both of my burning and breaking my Sword, Piſtols, and Musket, and the ſpoiling the Barrel of Powder, as alſo the burning the Bible termed the Word of GOD by ignorants, not knowing GOD. And if any Man do wonder at its burning, it is becauſe his ſoul knoweth not the LORD that bought him: and further, his Name is not write in the book of life; for all wonder and marvel, and admiration it is until CHRIST be come; but when Faith is planted, wonderment ſeſſeth, GOD reigns, Man is made obedient, then as he made an idol depending upon that dead Letter. Chriſt is the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:133404:4"/>living life of righteouſneſs, which is the ſpiritual life, invalved under them dark expreſſions; and when CHRIST is come, the Soul is Goſpel, GOD's voice is ſounded, the new Creation erected, <hi>Adam</hi> reſtored to his firſt ſight. There is the whole Myſtery of the Goſpel's Hiſtory, theſe Words are true Scripture, The Letter killeth; but the Spirit of JESUS CHRIST is life eternal, opening dark dead men into the Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion with the Father.</p>
               <p>Therefore all People, Tongues and Nations, Know, That I did not burn the BIBLE in contempt of GOD, or in contempt of its Record from GOD, for then I had condemned my own life, which is framed in obe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience unto that litteral expreſſion; but thus I had made an Idol of the BIBLE, becauſe its living life was not then roſe in me, although thus much I had offered for the glory in the Goſpel contained.</p>
               <p>Thus I forſook my Trade, made Reſtoration accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to God's command upon me, forſook all glory of this World, went out from men, became a Nazarite un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to God, yet all this was but ſhort.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:133404:4"/>
               <p>TAke notice people, who amongſt you are come thus far, and all people know, you are no neerer GOD, then light is to darkneſs, for all your praying, preaching nor hearing; but ſo far as in Truth you practice GOD's command, and you muſt be in the Faith of JESUS before any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedience can ſtand, and this work doth wholly undoe mans wiſdom, and inlets GOD's righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs.</p>
               <p>If you ſay, I burned the word of GOD.</p>
               <p>I ſay, the Word of GOD cannot be burned, for it's GOD's Righteouſneſs in my Soul planted, and unto Men by my life declared in theſe Words, <hi>Sell all that you have, and give unto the poor, and fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low me:</hi> Do you not all know this to be true Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture? No, it is not true in you until you in obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence ſo act, that the life of GOD may reign in your mortal bodyes; for ye are to be wholly clean in Body, Soul, and Spirit, and this Trial I ſtate to try you by, yea, moſt have high Names in your mouths, but whoſe heart is freed from covetouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs? ye ſee GOD is holy, are ye not luſtful? who amongſt you all doth know one woman onely, for production of life; but ye are whore-maſters and whores ſaith Jehovah, that do know and not bring forth.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:133404:5"/>
               <p>THus ſaith GOD, The dogs and toads are that you count the baſeſt in the Creation, is clean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er then all men and woman under heaven; for they act onely for life, and ye for your abominable luſts.</p>
               <p>Thus take notice, what can be begotten, after he childe doth in the wombe teſtifie the act.</p>
               <p>But thus ſaith God, he will cleanſe the earth from all this beaſtly luſt, by fire, by ſword, by famine, by plague, and peſtilence, and ſcropian diſeaſes, till it be conſumed unto his beautiful State, which the burning the Lord's tent doth configurate; for all things of never ſo great worth or curioſity will God deſtroy until he come unto his ſtate of beauty, and that is his own righteouſneſs which will be Chriſt's reign a thouſand yeers according to the record, for every word muſt have ſpiritual fulfil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling and litteral alſo, which is Monarch the fifth, the Jews Lords, the earth reſtored, for Jehovah ſhall reign on Mount Sion, and the holy Law ſhall go forth of Jeruſalem.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:133404:5"/>
               <p>NOw I ſhall declare the truth of Jehovahs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand unto me thus, three dayes before I came down to the Houſe, the name I know not by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of its Caſtrophe, ing, ing, ing, thus my body fainted, and my ſpirit in me retained ſcarce ſtrength to move my frame, &amp; then my teeth beat in my head as the fierceſt ague that ever fell on man, my knees ſmote together, my hands quaked, and my water fell from me, for the preſence of God was terrible unto me; then came the word of Jehovah, and ſaid unto me, go down and ſlay the rebels againſt me, and make ſharp thy ſword, for they have broken their Covenants, and ſtand with their ſwords, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing we will break our Covenants in which our ſouls are bound unto God; then I cryed, O Lord wilt thou deſtroy the righteous with the wicked? and the Lords wrath was kindled againſt me, and and ſaid, go execute my wrath on the rebels againſt me. Then the Lord commanded to burn his Tent onely ſave the Tent ſtaff, and burn the Prieſts gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, with all that I had; whereupon I began to burn many things, and my own books, for all books do but image the life of ſome thing from the life expreſſing the true thing, and are dead idols when you come to dy, what good can all the written books in the world do you, they are but dead let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, nay living men cannot ſave you, and except Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus Chriſt dwell in you; yea are reprobates, for he onely is the word of God that was made fleſh, and he is the reconciler unto the father, I and my Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther are one, ſo the Scripture and the word of God
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:133404:6"/>abideth for ever and cannot be divided, but it doth divide all dividings, and indraw all dividings into one unity <hi>Satis Rex.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Then the Lord ſaid when I was burning and got men to help me, Stay thine hand thy ſacrifice is ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted; then I burnt no more, the multitude began to rage, and I ſaid, may not I do what I will with my own? and I brought my gown, and before all the people this was my ſhrine of ſhift in and by my trade I did cheat and cozen the people, and threw it in the fire, and ſaid whoſoever doth not in all he doth perſerve every mans good, equall with his own, is a thief and a murderer, which is but thus much, Love thy neighbor as thy ſelf, this is the Goſpel where it is acted; and the day before I came over and returned back, becauſe they were gone, and that night the Lord did command me to hire two pair of Oars, the one to carry me over &amp; to ſtay on me both till I came back, and give them twelve ſhillings for their day, and ſaid unto them it is the King of Iſraels pay, and know I cannot go over under, ſo hath the Lord commanded me when I come by water, and my pay and purſe would ſcarce before given two pence.</p>
               <p>This is the truth, Jehovah is my witneſs: now when I had don burning, the people did rage ſo, that I was fain to go to boat with my ſword drawn, and one <hi>Rowle Tichburn</hi> with me, and I borrowed an old ſword for him to have in his hand, but he knew nothing at all, onely my ſafty from the people that did ſtone us in the boat, and I cannot go without a a gard by reaſon of the heathen rage, and imagine
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:133404:6"/>a vain thing, then I came thinking I had my petiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, but it was left on the table at home, and I came into the Loby, and ſpake to Maſter <hi>Hull,</hi> that he would help me to deliver it, and he ſaid any ſcivile curteſie he would do, but I muſt give it to a Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, and I ſaid I know no men their, preſently I went down by the Lords command, for he ſaid their was not enough, for all ſhould hear that the godly might fear. Then I went down unto the houſe, and had two meſs of broth and two pots of Ale for <hi>Tichburn</hi> and my ſelf, then I was comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded by Jehovah, for to go, and comming to the door, the door-keeper of the Loby preſſed me be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>twixt the door and the wall, whereupon I came in I ſliped of my cloak, and drew my ſword, and ran at him ſo hard, that the point came within a foot of the hand, and would not enter, then I ſwange my ſword round about to have killed all that was nigh me; then I run to the door and ſtrock it with my foot, and then they gat hold on me, and threw me down and took away my ſword and committed me, now ſince God hath ſhewn me his meaning which is thus, he gideth and governeth all things, and cauſed me to preach his wrath that is kindled againſt you all, to cut you off clean from the earth, onely for a ſmall ſeed of his ſpirit detracted it; but as Jehovah lives, if they ſeparate not themſelves, you ſhall all fall together, becauſe the Lord cauſed me to preach to them the danger they are in, with the hazard of my life. Lift not up your heads, ye rebellious ſons of wrath, for thus ſaith Jehovah that I ſhall with that ſword and my ſtaſſe, although
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:133404:7"/>it would not cut them, I ſhall fight with an hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred of Baals champions, <hi>I</hi> mean the chief Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant-breakers, thoſe that robbed the ſouldier of his due earned wages, or them that felloniouſly ſtole the faith of the Nation, with the promting, prating Prieſts, and by this combate, the whole earth ſhall know who is God, <hi>Thau Rex Iſrael,</hi> let Jehovah raign over all rebellious fleſh.</p>
               <p>But my hand ſhall not touch any of you, except as is ſtated, and for this let all people that fear the Lord, praiſe the Lord that hath tryed his <hi>Anointed</hi> unto the death, and yet hath kept his hand from the life taking away of any one; and though my hands ſhall be clean, you ſhall not eſcape, Jehovah hath ſworn it, therefore you that fear the Lord aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly not your ſelves for lucre, nor any end, for if ye will not hear by Jehovah, when God doth bring the man ſlayer, he ſhall make no difference becauſe you have been warned, and ye harden your necks againſt the holy God that would ſave you. Take warning, take warning, take warning, fear, tremble, and depart their place and company, leaſt ye be partakers of their plagues.</p>
               <p>Now all people ſee your liberty by my preſident amongſt wicked men your lord rulers, by their own unjuſt laws: they ſent for me to examine me before a Committee, and ſome friends were at priſon, and went along with me, but becauſe of their wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, they are fearful of every winde, and accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to their wills, eſtabliſh for our Engliſh laws; no man muſt hear me examined, but one or two preſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed in. The firſt queries were frivolus, as where I
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:133404:7"/>lived, and had I not been at <hi>Rome,</hi> and my clothes did did trouble them, and they asked me who gave me money for my clothes, I anſwered by their ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that queſtion they were free from charity, for they were to clothe the naked and feed the hungry. Then they did aske why were my ſleeves ſo laced, I ſaid it was the Glob in the foure Spheres hold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and I told them that they were no wiſer then before. The next was, why was the cullor green? I ſaid it was the ancient Forreſter of England (all people take notice) and I did and would claim the whole Forreſt land of <hi>Albian,</hi> now named England, in my predeceſſors <hi>Barron Toni,</hi> then people crowd<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in, and they were afraid to ſit any longer, I ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peal unto their conſciences.</p>
               <p>Then at night when none could know I was ſent for, and no man but themſelves there, then they asked me where they left: then came the Spirit of God upon me, and gave me both courage and wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, for God never fails, if you one him ſurely de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend; then I ſaid <hi>I</hi> would declare the Lords word, my command faithfully, and then they could not have any power to harm me; but if <hi>I</hi> ſhould keep back one word then their ſpirits would enter upon me to harm me. And this is the word from Jeho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vah that came unto <hi>Theauraujon Taunijah,</hi> now na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med from Jehovah, <hi>Thau Rex</hi> Iſrael.</p>
               <p>Theſe words <hi>I</hi> ſaid before them, the Lord com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded me to come down, ſaying, <hi>GO SLAY THE RECELS AGAINST ME;</hi> for they have broken their Covenants, and ſtand with their ſwords in their hands, ſaying we will break all our Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:133404:8"/>with the Lord, unto whom our ſouls ſtand bound.</p>
               <p>Then <hi>I</hi> ſaid, Lord will thou ſlay the godly with the wicked?</p>
               <p>Then one of the Members of their own making, ſaid what Covenant have we broken.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Anſw.</hi> Then <hi>I</hi> ſaid thus ſaith the Lord, do not ask what Covenant have you broken, but what one of all them Covenants your ſouls ſtand bound unto God, have you kept? Then they anſwered and ſaid, this man can preach: yea, ſaid <hi>I</hi> five times, three times at <hi>Eltham,</hi> and two times at <hi>Lambeth,</hi> and now your Funeral Sermon, for thus ſaith the Lord, ye are accurſed before Jehovah, and he will cut you off root and branch, for have you not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demned to death, and your ſelves raign by the ſame law. Then they ſaid, Why is my Lord Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tectors wayes perverſe and accurſed before God? Thus God hath ſhewn me, that ye all are but my Lord Protector, minde, you all and the reſt are but my Lord Protector, for know you all, that except you write his coppy, you cannot ſit here.</p>
               <p>Then they ſaid, how ſhould they know it was the word of God that <hi>I</hi> ſpake? Thus ſaid <hi>I</hi> ſhall ye know it, if my words do not ſmite you, and ye are righteous men, then my words are from the divel, wright me this down, this is mine; then the Chairman wrote the words, <hi>I</hi> repeating them. Thus ſhall you know it to be Gods word, if my words do not ſmite you, and ye are righteous men, then my words are from the devil. Then <hi>I</hi> cryed aloud and ſaid, if any man did fear God, let him
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:133404:8"/>praiſe God that had tryed me even to death, and <hi>I</hi> had not ſlain any man, and now my hand ſhould be clean from the blood of them, but God would raiſe Butchers: then they ſaid, who were the But<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chers, then <hi>I</hi> ſaid <hi>I</hi> will tell you who they are, they are the ſouldiers whom you have cozened and chea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, your armies ſhall divide, and they ſhall hew you aſſunder, and cut you off root and branch, therefore if there be any that fear God, depart from among the accurſed men, for God will cut them off and their children, and not leave one of them to piſs on the earth.</p>
               <p>Then they ſaid, why did not <hi>I</hi> execute Gods com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand? <hi>I</hi> ſaid God accept the will for the deed, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance <hi>Abraham,</hi> then two roſe and ſaid <hi>I</hi> had ſaid that God had accepted my ſacrifice or offering, <hi>I</hi> denyed their words they affirmed, and upon my illuſtrative they ſtated a poſition, and bid the Chairman wright it down, and ſo to have taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way my life, becauſe <hi>I</hi> had convinced them by Gods truth, yet their wickedneſs is ſo great, that they defie the Lord that bought them, even unto his very face, ſtill thoſe two men affirmed a poſition in plain terms, them which would have taken away my life by their falſe witneſſing, proved thus, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe God did ſtay their Chairmans hand, and two men, one of my right hand, and one on my left, gave teſtimony that delivered me from my death, and ſaid my words were not poſitive, which knew all men, the laws, all poſition. As thus for doing in ſuch a thing, ſuch an puniſhment, but yea aſſes know for ſuch an entention, if it had truely been
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:133404:9"/>the law cannot lay hold, and know there can be no treaſon againſt all traytors, and that lies behind to come in its place, you will ſay and judge <hi>Theaurau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>john</hi> did write this book, <hi>I</hi> ſee them that know me in the ſpirit do know <hi>I</hi> did write this book, but they that would know me litterally ſhall not know <hi>I</hi> write this book, and yet know you all <hi>I</hi> did write this book, but whether dead or alive, you know not, this is one of your own, but it is beyond your form: hear ye cheaters of the nations liberty <hi>I</hi> write, and no man ſees, how can any of your per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jured ones, ſay he ſaw me ſpell theſe words, write the letters that doth contain my meaning, then it goes unto the Prieſts, then it is another thing, and ſuch a thing that no law in England can lay hold upon. Thus my copy is conſumed to give glory unto the Prieſts; the Printer he printeth the copy, he dare not ſwear that he that gives him the coppy, ſaw him write the copy, its his trade to print, and by the free Law of England, every man may uſe his lawful calling without molleſtation, elſe ye fools where is the grand Charter of <hi>Albion,</hi> now named England.</p>
               <p>Know all men God doth command to honor theſe three men, the Chairman and the two men on each ſide, and <hi>I</hi> my ſelf do give unto each of them their due reſpect, as they were true witneſſes of my true words, and ſo ſaved my life: and thus ſaith Jeho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vah, that when his Buchers, the man ſlayer ſhall ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute his juſt judgement on the reſt; their life <hi>I</hi> have given unto them for a pray, but their eſtates are gone becauſe of a confederaſie with the ſons of <hi>Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lial,</hi>
                  <pb n="17" facs="tcp:133404:9"/>their names I will declare to the whole king<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom for their honor; ſo ſoon as I know their names, for I knew not one man but Maſter <hi>Hull,</hi> as I went by into the room.</p>
               <p>The next and laſt was this, I did beſeech them conſider that a man of peace, a man that had for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaken all, that God ſhould raiſe him up for to teſtifie with the hazard of his life, Gods fierce wrath kindled againſt them, to cut them off quite from the earth. Then one anſwered and ſaid, I fought with Colonel <hi>Rich;</hi> then I ſaid, Gentlemen I beſeech you all to hear me in this matter, then they heard me attentively, then I ſaid, that when Colonel <hi>Rich</hi> and Captain <hi>French</hi> that villain, with the reſt of the theeves came to divide their theeviſh purchaſes, the Parks, in which they had cheated the poor ſouldiers, by buying their debenters for a ſong in compariſon of their due right, for Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen, I ſaid, thus, if I ſet a man to work till it comes unto twenty ſhillings, and then give him ten graots, I count them cheating theeves and villains. What do you think of this? At this word they were mute, and asked me what I was, and if I loved the Quakers, and I ſaid they were honeſt men, then they made ſtrange, then I ſaid, I love all, as an Independent, Anabaptiſt, Papiſt, Cavileer, and all men, if they were but what they ſaid, but for to ſpeak good words, and under them good pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tences wrong and ſpoil others, them my ſoul did abhor and loath. Gentlemen, I am a man that doth acknowledge a State of Kings, Earls, Barons, and Lords, which is Monarchy the fifth, Chriſt ſhall
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:133404:10"/>a thouſand yeers. This that I now write, is added, for to give the land notice from Jehovah, I do from the Lord according unto our lineal diſſent, as before the land it ſhall be proved our right, to be royal, lineal, duely, without tranſpoſition, claim the crown of England, and by the which true right, undoubtedly, when the records do appear, and from that true right I do voice forth unto the world, though in priſon a degraſion of all honors conferred on and upon any perſon honorable or worſhipful from the day and yeer of the life, act<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the Duke of <hi>Gloceſter,</hi> named <hi>Richard</hi> the third Englands King, and alſo I degrad all title of <hi>Henry</hi> the ſeventh, as none in heritance in Englands crown right, by which cheat <hi>Stuard</hi> came in by marriage of <hi>Henry</hi> the ſevenths daughter, and in this degraid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment lies the reſt degraded, and an annihilated, for by Jehovah every man ſhall have his due right, and my ſelf not one farthing: and not my ſelf, nor mine children and people one penny, for I go to a grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter inheritance, which is <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> onely I do re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain my due right and title <hi>Albiton</hi> or <hi>Albion,</hi> that is, the lands reſtoring, the oppreſſor cut off, the people ſhall praiſe God that made them, when by righteouſneſs they are reſtored.</p>
               <p>Take notice all people of England, although by a Divine right I do challenge and claim the whole Forreſt lands, as we ſhall prove in a lawful Seſſions of the Nations juſt chouſing, and alſo our Roy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al title of <hi>Albanugaunny,</hi> The which title doth in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude the Crown of England: yet all people know we do ſcorn that our title Royal ſhould be expoſtu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lated
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:133404:10"/>with our younger brothers ſervants or jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niman, I mean my Lord Protector, and his choſing by him ſtated, for I tell you the name <hi>Cromwell</hi> doth degraid him <hi>Williams,</hi> will not hold him, but I know that had not he tranſgreſſed all Jehovahs commands; he is bigger, greater, and higher by a true lineal ſigne, then he is in his aſſention of his full right, and whereas my life was jeparded for to declare a meſſage from Jehovah to him now, if he would give his whole riches, I would not ſee his face, for the Lord hath determined to cut him off root and branch, becauſe he hath hardened his heart againſt the Lord, for the Lords word to me was his ſafty, if he would have obayed and an in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crew of honor rightly ſtated, but he hath forſaken the day of mercy, therefore cut him now off, ſo ſaith Jehovah.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="letter">
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:133404:11"/>
               <head>This is the copy of a Letter ſent to the Houſe.</head>
               <opener>
                  <salute>Mr. Speaker,</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>
                  <hi>MY requeſt unto the houſe is, that I may have an aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignement from your houſe, that I may with my keeper attend the Houſe for right from the Houſe, againſt two Traytors in conſiſtancy to morrow, being Thurſday, which I ſhall make charge againſt, for my charge and crime is but breach of Peace, for which I have ſuffered impriſonment, and it cannot be breach of peace if you had not broken your Covenants, becauſe a free Parliament, a free egreſs unto that Parliament. And know you all, that a door unto the door is a breach of the ſubjects liberty, and for the breach of the ſubjects liberty, I do demand juſtice upon that door keeper that broke my peace in preſsing me betwixt the door and the wall, in coming for right un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to I know not what to name, and againſt my liberty, the lands cauſe, I drew my ſword, I deſire that I may have li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty with my keeper, to go to my Lord Protector, for the Lord hath ſo commanded me, That he ſet his foot upon my neck, if in me be iniquity, let him ſlay me, or cauſe me to be put to death, for I labor to the Cauſe and wave the Effect.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Thau Iſrael Rex.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>This letter was ſent preſently after the cheat by night that commanded me to be brought before them, and the Lord commanded me for to buy a lock and a chain, ſaying, I do binde thee to ſtand by them, and as this chain and lock is my burden upon thee, ſo are them aſſembled rebells againſt me and alſo againſt the Goſpel, Law, and all good mens liberty: thou ſhalt keep the lock and give them the key, and I will bring again by thee Englands li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty:
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:133404:11"/>ſo the lock is on my legg night and day till approach our liberty. And this is a word from Jehovah unto the aſſembly of rebels that have for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſworn their own vows in which their ſouls was bound unto me ſaith the Lord, they are accurſed catterpillers, ſmiting the labour of every innocent; and thus ſaith God that knoweth all things, in whoſe hands is life and death, the life of mans ſoul after the diſſolution of the body, that formed the morning unto all beings, that gave Paradice its be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the high Spheres Celeſtial, that hangeth the Globe in its four Spheres, that concentreth the air in every breath, that maketh the wind the life in cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation. Thus ſaith the Lord, that you ſcorn with your whole ſoul, ſaying, we will eſtabliſh our way, our courſe ſhall proſper, and we will raign, although ye have oppreſſed the poor, cozened the rich, deceived all, and aſſumed the Nations Title, birth right, law, liberty, and godlineſs hath fetcht this deſign. Ye reprobates, ſaith Jehovah, ought not you to have been ſervants in your due rights, and not ſinners a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt me, who am your life? but you have contem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned righteouſneſs, juſtice, truth and equity, and your everlaſting ſalvation, which conſiſteth in a holy o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedience unto my holy will revealed in my litteral word, and you hypocrites have made my litteral word your ſtalking-horſe, that thereby you might erect your covetous practice. O ye villains and traytors againſt me, ſaith God, do you remember your houling, and your hypocritical faces that you formed, that by that you might in ſnare the honeſt godly men and women to deceive them?</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:133404:12"/>
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <hi>Thus ſaith God that formed all things and beings that he ſent his ſervant to ſhew you high tranſgreſsions which he wil not forgive becauſe you have murdered his ſervants that did and do teſtifie the truth of actings unto your face; ſhould ye not ſaith God have humbled your ſelves in ſack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloth and aſhes thereby to have ſtaid the fierce wrath that is kindled againſt you, but ye the higheſt rebels that ever the earth bore, yet ye lift up your ſelves for all your tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſsions, and to the very face of your Maker, ſay what covenant have we broke, and your conſciences witneſs in you you have broken all that ever you made. O houl ye dogs for your day of vengeance is now come for to cut you off root and branch, and cleanſe the earth from its oppreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors and oppreſsion.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Thus ſaith God he himſelf will plead his ſervants cauſe; you ſay that he offended very high, and not to be paralleled. I Jehovah, ſaith my God, do teſtifie you are the cauſe and he obeyed my command faithfully therefore will I honor my ſervant Iſraels King, the whole earth over and the Angels ſhall ſing hallilujahes in his praiſe</hi> Sebab almam almarrauim mugmahhuhm Sebarte Caſti. <hi>For he hazarded his life to free his ſoul from his engage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in the lands cauſe which he covenant with the honeſt party at the firſt beginning, he bore faithful witneſs to your faces, when you by no right could call him before you, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe you had betrayed the nation juſts truſt unto you com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, did not he teſtifie that he ſtood with you in cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant till you had all forſworn your ſelves, and have you not; let God and the land witneſs; then you began to rage at him, he ſaid do not rage, he did not care one farthing for you all, for you were all collered and could go no fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther then God would permit, and ſaid he knew you all did
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:133404:12"/>Gods work though you knew it not, this was in the onely high Committee that dare let none hear nor ſee what they did.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Look to it, God pleads with you himſelf by mortal man, and ſaith, that if you were all ſlain the covenant were kept, our ſouls diſengaged that now unto God ſtand bound for to maintain righteouſneſs, juſtice, truth, and equity, in them words lies our ſouls bound that covenanted againſt the Kings party: your power cut off, the land freed from perjurers, the liberty gained, the land reſtored covenant-breakers executed, and every man freed from you the oppreſſors, and untill this be done every mans ſoul ſtands bound into God to receive eternal puniſhment, for ſo high an engagement, therefore ſee unto your ſelves every man, God is juſt and will not clear the guilty. Thus ſaith the Lord that formed the heart in man, that it is death by all</hi> Englands <hi>law, for you to aſſume and preſume for to ſit in that houſe without being rightly choſen duely in truſt, with whole free conſent, the nations right, ſtill inherent in your maſters who ſet you there, and do defend you in their right there ſitting, and all knows you have robbed your maſters, aſſumed their right, and now give them your wills for</hi> Englands <hi>true laws, and ſay we the Parliament of England, are the commonwealth of England when the God of heaven, and the people in the lands know you to be Traytors to both theſe themſelves, and your own ſouls, for God doth ſay I will cut off the Covenant-braker from the earth, wicked men ſhall not live half their time, as for my Lord Protector, his is but a derivative Conmiſsion, though he make it carry all by his ſuperlative motion, if he ſay he hath obtained it by ſtrength, bid him look: Was not the Commons his bottom? Therefore, O man know thy foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation,
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:133404:13"/>and humble ſubmiſsion, that though thy body falls by the people againſt whom thou haſt ſo highly tranſgreſſed, that thy ſoul may have ſome eaſe for all thy wilful murders, for if not ſatisfaction here, you ſhall ſatisfie Gods divine juſtice after death, till every one by you wronged, be duly ſatisfied.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Now ye Jews my people, know that our</hi> Jah <hi>by his power declared in</hi> Elokim, <hi>will manifeſt his high deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verance this yeer, beginning at the twenty third day of</hi> December, <hi>but my</hi> Jehovah <hi>commanded me to name that day the firſt day of the moneth</hi> AB, <hi>which doth hold the whole import of the whole Alphabet Hebraick, as the Fathers houſe, or the father indrawing his houſe, or the houſe indrawn into the father,</hi> Vivat Rex.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>Now hear my people <hi>Iſrael</hi> and <hi>Judah,</hi> this do <hi>I</hi> command from high, holy, and dreadful, ſacred Jehovah, which holy name I command, ye do not mention in your mouths, leaſt the Lord ſlay you for your preſumption; this is my command upon you, that you ſeparate your ſelves inwardly and outwardly, and every one that believes <hi>Iah</hi> to be faithful in his covenant made unto our fathers, that he would gather us unto our own land, and the Temple ſhall be new built in that ſtately high glory that al glory before is not worth the naming, which holy pattern <hi>I</hi> have in its living intrinſecality, and provide every one a Tent, a Tent, Tent, Tent, Tent, Tent, Tent, for thus ſaith your <hi>Iah,</hi> That his holy Angel ſhall ſmite this land, and ſecurity will be no in place, therefore take no thought, only ſeparate your ſelves, and be wholy in your ſelves, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nounce
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:133404:13"/>the world and all worldlineſs: for God is now trying all fleſh by his pure law, which is fire. Therefore hear, and obey, and your ſouls ſhall live; this is the Lords command upon you, that you obſerve a day of reſtraint of minde, which is a figure pointing to a new Sabbath, and the day is this, beginning the twenty third day of <hi>December,</hi> which is the firſt day of the firſt moneth, named <hi>AB,</hi> and count from that till you make a ſeventh, and bring your count to this command, and ſo go on keeping a ſeventh, till I do command the draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the whole diſperſed into one body together, for which command, at this time I from the Lord ſhall receive and know you my people to the worlds blinding, that the drawing my ſword, conſider the act, it holds thus much, that Jehovah by my hand will deliver the captive Jews, and my hand ſhall unto Jehovahs glory build the Temple, and recover the <hi>Germane</hi> State, to ſtate every Prince and Peer in his due holdment, according unto the command of the Lord, Who is, who is: for <hi>Leo Septtentris</hi> whom the Lord hath raiſed, the earth to reſtore, the families to place the Church, in earth to rectifie, and the Jews to make Lords over <hi>omnia Terra</hi> and <hi>Tri,</hi> but unto Jeruſalem all muſt pay, no King, no Prince, no Peer ſhall ſtand but by tribute unto the holy land. <hi>Than.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Further take notice all people, that I do from the Lord declare a reſtoration unto <hi>Maria,</hi> late Queen of <hi>England,</hi> for God hath conſidered her ſufferings, but 'tis Eaſtward: and thus faith God,
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:133404:14"/>as her womb hath brought forth by luft unto death, it ſhall bring forth perfectly unto the glory of God, but ſhe muſt, fathers houſe, children, and kindred, all forſake, for on them all for God ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geance take: for <hi>Rome</hi> now no more ſhall be, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe of her idolatry, nor <hi>Venice,</hi> nor <hi>Napels,</hi> nor <hi>Conſtantinople,</hi> nor <hi>Paris;</hi> there is a ſymptone Hyro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliphycally tipifying, more including.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>Hear my people, I require and command an of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fering from the greateſt unto the leaſt, for to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide our Tent Royal, which is the Seat of Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in our Tribes, and the remainder is for the poor people that have no houſe nor bread, for they come firſt to me.</p>
               <p>And ye great ones in England, by Jehovah, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you go out of England ſhall be all even, for one ſix pence of this accurſed money ſhall not croſs the water into <hi>France;</hi> for whoſo doth diſobey my command, he dyes ſo ſoon as we are over, but as the Lords ſanctification is in you, ſo doth the Lord by my hand ſtate you. But for my brethren the Jews beyond the Seas, 'tis another thing, for there is many weapons of war to be made according to its pattern received and wrote in the book of the Law, but no Guns, nor Powder, nor Bullets, nor any Armes of Engliſh faſhion, for that is a curſe upon us, the very land we muſt not name; but thus, the land of the North in which we were ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry long held, ſerving the heathen idols for the li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving <hi>Addonia:</hi> for know all on earth, that <hi>Leo Ori,</hi>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:133404:14"/>is <hi>Iuda</hi> ſtated, which is the heavens fixed into their received nature, and <hi>Leo Septentrionalis</hi> is the hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens Ragation, which is <hi>Iuda</hi> in captivity. So though I write <hi>Leo Septentrio, I</hi> am being reſtored <hi>Leo Ori,</hi> and my Sination is the beautous ſtar <hi>Select</hi> an ſecret <hi>Pecajah,</hi> named <hi>Orion;</hi> ſo that my people, my command is, that in your offering, you ſhew your ſelves with a good heart, leaſt in the day of calamity you cry and ſay, O that our hearts had been larger in extending unto our bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren, for a Tent is a houſe for a family, and many of your chief advocaters have no houſe nor bread, and theſe be they that are the firſt fruites unto God, as my ſelf am, and hath been a Naza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rite unto my Jehovah this five yeers, onely inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceding for my peoples ſins, for their expiation, and let the earth know, I have neither houſe nor bread, but from my people whom God hath given to know me in the ſpirits unity, but very few know my work. Seperate, ſeperate, ſeperate, ſeperate, ſeperate, ſeperate, ſeperate. Come out of her, come of her, come out of her, come out of her, come out of her, come out of her, come out of her, come out of her, come out of her, leaſt ye be partakers of her plagues, for the hour of exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of her denounced judgement is to be pou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red on her ſuddainly, ſuddainly, ſuddainly; flye out of her Amies, flye out of her Armies, flye out of her Armies, flye out of her Armies, flye out her Armies, flye out her Armies, flye out of her Armies, flye out of her Armies, for vengeance is
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:133404:15"/>coming, flye out of her ſhips, flye out of her ſhips, flye out of her ſhips, flye out of her ſhips, flye out of her ſhips, for deſolation is decreed on her, flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities; flye out of her Cities, flye out of her Cities, for her vengeance ſhall upon her ceaſe: Touch not her trading, touch not her trading, touch not her trading, touch not her trading, touch not her trading, touch not her trading, touch not her trading, for her ſins puniſhment ſhall be pour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed upon her, as is witneſſed by all the holy pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets and Apoſtles, ſhe ſhall receive double ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to her tranſgreſments for all her fornicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, whoredomes, wherewith ſhe hath deceived all Nations.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>I</hi> ſhall be at peace in England, but I diſown any Power to be lawful now in being, for the maſters are robbed, the ſervant rule, and truth is caſt out of their ſchool. Now I declare, being that the Lord hath freed my ſoul by my hazard of my life, to free my ſoul from my Covenant ingaged with the honeſt meaning men in the wars beginning. I do promiſe I will break no law, but live in peace, neither will I obay any traytors command, for whoſoever ſhall come to me with any name or war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant from I know not what named themſelves Parliament or Commonwealth of England, <hi>I</hi> will duely reſiſt and ſlay or be ſlain; therefore I warn all that fear God, for coming to ſerve or cite me to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear:
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:133404:15"/>then let the heathen Covenant-brakers come as many as they will, <hi>I</hi> weigh them not, for the Lord is with me to defend his own right: all people, whereas the whole envy my life, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe I have told them the truth, if they take away my life, then know that there is the living God, but if by me one inſtrument, and in their cuſtody do diſperſe them, and bring a judgement upon them, then let the whole earth unanimouſly praiſe in ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledgement that the God of Iſrael is the living <hi>Addoni,</hi> the tryal is ſtated by</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>ThauRam Tanjah Rex Iſrael &amp; Angliſe.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div type="postscript">
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:133404:16"/>
               <p>WRote in the night by the ſeeing eye that doth unfold all villany. You ſhal never know who wrote this, but my people know I wrote this, and there can be no oath where there can be no ſeeing; and ye aſſes know <hi>I</hi> ſcorn the oath <hi>Ex oficio,</hi> which ye degraded in name and practice, in its nature that ſtate holds all your actings.</p>
               <p>Who is for the holy wars, beginning at <hi>France?</hi> This original coppy came to my hand in priſon, and <hi>I</hi> will pay for its printing, for the good of all, that the wicked may ceaſe from his wickedneſs, and the righteous may ſeparate and act forth his faith by his works. The ends are good, <hi>Thau.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
